<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<FactList>
  <Facts>
    <Fact name="Heart,Ulna,Radius"> <!-- 0 -->
     

      <FactA>
        Heart:
        The heart is protected by the ribs.

        The heart pumps blood through the body.

        Blood provides oxygen and nutrients to the body.

        Cardiology is the study of the heart.

        The ratio of red blood cells to white is 600:1.
      </FactA>

      <FactB>
       Ulna:
       The ulna is one of the two bones in the forarm.
       
       The ulna is larger than the radius. 

       The ulna spans from the elbow to the wrist.

       It is one of the three bones that form the elbow. 

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
       Radius:
       The radius is only slightly shorter than the ulna.

       The radius shares the side of the arm with the thumb. 

       The radius is wider at the wrist than the ulna.

       It is one of the three bones that form the elbow.

      </FactC>

    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Lungs,Humerus,Kneecap"> <!-- 1 -->

      <FactA>
        Lungs:
        Humans inhale about 4,015,000 liters of air annually.

        Special cells in lungs produce mucus.

        Pulmonology is the study of the lung.

        Polluted air darkens the lungs.
      </FactA>

      <FactB>
       Humerus:
       The largest bone in the arm is the humerus.
       
       The only bone in the upper arm is the humerus. 

       The end of the humerus forms the shoulder.

       The humerus becomes twice as wide at the elbow.

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        Kneecap:
        The patella is known as the kneecap.
        
        Twelve muscles are needed for the knee to function.
        
        Thick cartilage covers the back of the knee.
        
        The kneecap is not connected to a joint.


      </FactC>
    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Spine,Trachea,foot"> <!-- 2 -->

      <FactA>
        Spine:
        The human spine has 26 vertebrae:
        7 cervical vertebrae,
        12 thoracic vertebrae,
        5 lumbar vertebrae,
        1 sacrum,
        1 tailbone.

        Humans can’t live without the spine.

        The spine has nerve clusters linked to the brain.


      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        Trachea:
        The trachea is a four-inch-wide tube near the lungs.
        
        The trachea's diameter is less than an inch.
        
        The trachea has cartilage rings surrounding it.
        
        As one breathes in, the trachea widens.



      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        Feet:
        The toes contain metatarsals and phalanges.
        
        The metatarsals are longer than the phalanges.
        
        The calcaneus or heel bone is the largest bone in the foot.
        
        The talus bone in the foot supports the leg.


      </FactC>


    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Ribs"> <!-- 3 -->

      <FactA>
        Ribs:
        Ribs protect many internal organs.

        Ribs expand with the lungs.

        Ribs are made from bone and cartilage.

        The first seven ribs are considered "true ribs".

        "True ribs" attach to the sternum directly.

      </FactA>



    </Fact>





    <Fact name="Brain,Collar Bones, hip"> <!-- 4 -->

      <FactA>

        Brain:
        The largest part of the brain is the cerebrum.

        Other parts include:
        corpus callosum,
        cerebral cortex,
        thalamus,
        cerebellum,
        hypothalamus,
        hippocampus,
        brainstem.

        Cerebrospinal fluid shields the brain from impact.

        Yawning is the brain's way of cooling itself down.

      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        Collar bone:
        The clavicle is also known as the collar bone.
        
        The clavicle is the only horizontal long bone.
        
        The clavicle keeps shoulder blade in place.
        
        It is derived from the Latin word meaning little key.


      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        Hip:
        The hip supports the digestive track.

        The hip joint is a ball and socket joint.
        
        A "broken hip" is actually a broken tip of the Femur.


      </FactC>

    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Skull,shoulderblade"> <!-- 5 -->

      <FactA>
        Skull:
        Cerebrospinal fluid is in the skull.

        The skull protects the brain.

        An infant's skull has 44 bones.

        The bones fuse so an adult's skull has 22 bones.

      </FactA>
      <FactB>
        Shoulder Blade:
        The shoulder blade is also known as the scapula.
        
        There are 17 muscles connected to the scapula.
        
        The scapula is the least commonly broken bone.

      </FactB>




    </Fact>
    <Fact name="Hand"> <!-- 6 -->

      <FactA>
        Hand:
        The fingers are composed of metacarpals and phalanges.
        
        The phalanges have three sections:
        proximal,
        middle,
        distal.
        
        There are no muscles in the fingers.
        
        The hands have an average of 27 bones.

      </FactA>


    </Fact>
    <Fact name="LegBones"><!-- 7 -->

      <FactA>
        Tibia:
        The bone that fractures most is the tibia.

        The tibia is larger than the fibula.

        The tibia is more commonly known as the shin bone.

        Most weight is supported by the tibia.


      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        Fibula:
        The fibula is smaller than the fibula.

        The fibula is more commonly known as the calf bone.

        The thinnest long bone in the human body is the fibula.

        The word fibula comes from a Latin word meaning clasp.

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        Femur:
        The longest bone in the human body is the femur.

        The strongest bone in the human body is the femur.

        The thigh only contains one bone: the femur.

        The femur can withstand over a ton of force.

        The femur extends from the hip to the knee.

      </FactC>

      <Fact name="Tibia"><!-- 8 -->

        <FactA>
          Tibia:
          The bone that fractures most is the tibia.
    
          The tibia is larger than the fibia.

          The tibia is more commonly known as the shin bone.

          Most weight is supported by the tibia.

        </FactA>
          
       
      </Fact>
      <Fact name="Fibula"> <!-- 9 -->

        <FactA>
          Fibula:
          Only two bones reside in the lower leg: the fibia and tibia.

          The fibia is smaller than the fibia.

          The fibia is more comonly known as the calf bone.

          The thinest longbone in the human body is the fibia.

          The word fibia comes from the latin, meaning broach or clasp.


        </FactA>
      </Fact>
      <Fact name="Femur"><!-- 10 -->

        <FactA>
          Femur:
          The longest bone in the human body is the femur.

          The strongest bone in the human body is the femur.

          The thigh only contains one bone: the femur.

          Over a ton of force can be applied to the femur without fracturing.

          The Femur extends from the hip to the knee.

        </FactA>
      </Fact>
    </Fact>


  </Facts>
</FactList>