<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<FactList>
  <Facts>
    <Fact name="Heart,Ulna,Radius"> <!-- 0 -->
     

      <FactA>
        Heart:
        The heart is protected by the ribs.

        The heart pumps blood through the body.

        Blood provides oxygen and nutrients to the body.

        Cardiology is the study of the heart.

        The ratio of red blood cells to white is 600:1.
      </FactA>

      <FactB>
       Ulna:
       The ulna is one of the two bones in the forarm.
       
       The ulna is larger than the radius. 

       The ulna spans from the elbow to the wrist.

       It is one of the three bones that form the elbow. 

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
       Radius:
       The radius is only slightly shorter than the ulna.

       The radius shares the side of the arm with the thumb. 

       The radius is wider at the wrist than the ulna.

       It is one of the three bones that form the elbow.

      </FactC>

    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Lungs,Humerus,Kneecap"> <!-- 1 -->

      <FactA>
        Lungs:
        Humans inhale about 4,015,000 liters of air annually.

        Special cells in lungs produce mucus.

        Pulmonology is the study of the lung.

        Polluted air darkens the lungs.
      </FactA>

      <FactB>
       Humerus:
       The largest bone in the arm is the humerus.
       
       The only bone in the upper arm is the humerus. 

       The end of the humerus forms the shoulder.

       The humerus becomes twice as wide at the elbow.

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        When humans breathe in or inhale,
        the lungs expand.
        This expansion is possible only
        when diaphragm squeezes.
        The diaphragm is actually a small
        dome-shaped
        muscles seated right below the lungs.
        You could live with just one lung,
        it will limit your physical ability,
        but you can still have normal life.
        The study of lung diseases is
        known as pulmonology.
        Asthma is a common disease that
        affects the lungs.
        Asthma attacks happen when your airways
        narrow after being irritated.
        The narrow airways make it hard
        for you to breathe in air.
        Pneumonia is a dangerous disease
        that makes it harder
        for your lungs to absorb oxygen
        from the air you breathe.
      </FactC>
    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Spine"> <!-- 2 -->

      <FactA>
        Spine:
        The human spine has 26 vertebrae:
        7 cervical vertebrae,
        12 thoracic vertebrae,
        5 lumbar vertebrae,
        1 sacrum,
        1 tailbone.

        Humans couldn't live without the spine.

        The spine has nerve clusters linked to the brain.

      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        The spinal cord is about 1 centimeter thick.
        Astronauts grow 1 or 2 inches upon returning
        from space because of gravity.
        The spinal cord has over 100 joints,
        at least 220 ligaments and over 120 total muscles.
        Babies have more vertebrae than adults,
        this is because some of the bones come
        together as we grow older.
        Giraffe's have the same number of
        cervical (neck) vertebrae as human's.
        If a spine were to be taken out of a human body,
        it can stand hundreds of kilograms.

      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        The spinal column is very important,
        it supports the weight of the body,
        it provide flexibility for movement,
        and is the central pathway for the nerves.
        One quarter of the spine is made of cartilage.
        There are 23 elastic disks between
        each of the vertebrae.
        These discs compress when we put pressure on them
        and decompress we the pressure is relieved.
        The disks have a cartridge casing, this helps the
        disk stay flexible,
        they also absorb the shocks that transfer to
        the spine when we are active.
      </FactC>


    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Ribs"> <!-- 3 -->

      <FactA>
        Ribs:
        Ribs protect many internal organs.

        Ribs expand with the lungs.

        Ribs are made from bone and cartilage.

        The first seven ribs are considered "true ribs".

        "True ribs" attach to the sternum directly.

      </FactA>



    </Fact>





    <Fact name="Brain"> <!-- 4 -->

      <FactA>

        Brain:
        The largest part of the brain is the cerebrum.

        Other parts include:
        corpus callosum,
        cerebral cortex,
        thalamus,
        cerebellum,
        hypothalamus,
        hippocampus,
        brainstem.

        Cerebrospinal fluid shields the brain from impact.

        Yawning is the brain's way of cooling itself down.

      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        The brain almost produces enough energy to light a light bulb.
        Yawning is the brain's way of cooling itself down.
        The brain is the only organ in the human body that has no nerves,
        so it can't feel any pain.
        The human brain is not as perfect as it is thought of since in many
        instances it has been found to fool human beings making them to perceive
        things differently from the reality.
        Your brain keeps developing until your late 40's.
        Your brain uses 20% of all the oxygen and blood in your body.
        Even though sometimes people say that the right part and
        left part of the brain are divided, they both actually work together.
        The frontal lobes control thinking, planning, organizing, problem solving,
        short-term memory and movement.
      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        The parietal lobes interpret sensory information,
        such as taste, temperature and touch.
        The occipital lobes process images from your eyes and
        link that information with images stored in memory.
        The temporal lobes process information from your senses of smell, taste and sound.
        They also play a role in memory storage.
        The cerebellum is the part of the brain that controls the sensory information
        like sight, sound, taste, smell, and hearing.
        The limbic system is the part of the brain that controls emotions and memories.
        The peripheral nervous system is the nerves that makes sure that your brain
        sends the right information to the right side of you body.
      </FactC>

    </Fact>

    <Fact name="Skull"> <!-- 5 -->

      <FactA>
        Skull:
        Cerebrospinal fluid is in the skull.

        The skull protects the brain.

        An infant's skull has 44 bones.

        The bones fuse so an adult's skull has 22 bones.

      </FactA>




    </Fact>
    <Fact name="Hand"> <!-- 6 -->

      <FactA>
        Hands:
        The hands consist of an average of 27 bones.

      </FactA>


    </Fact>
    <Fact name="LegBones"><!-- 7 -->

      <FactA>
        Tibia:
        The bone that fractures most is the tibia.

        The tibia is larger than the fibia.

        The tibia is more commonly known as the shin bone.

        Most weight is supported by the tibia.

      </FactA>

      <FactB>
        Fibula:
        

        The fibia is smaller than the fibia.

        The fibia is more comonly known as the calf bone.

        The thinest longbone in the human body is the fibia.

        The word fibia comes from the latin word meaning clasp.
      </FactB>

      <FactC>
        Femur:
        The longest bone in the human body is the femur.

        The strongest bone in the human body is the femur.

        The thigh only contains one bone: the femur.

        The femur can withstand over a ton of force.

        The femur extends from the hip to the knee.

      </FactC>

      <Fact name="Tibia"><!-- 8 -->

        <FactA>
          Tibia:
          The bone that fractures most is the tibia.
    
          The tibia is larger than the fibia.

          The tibia is more commonly known as the shin bone.

          Most weight is supported by the tibia.

        </FactA>
          
       
      </Fact>
      <Fact name="Fibula"> <!-- 9 -->

        <FactA>
          Fibula:
          Only two bones reside in the lower leg: the fibia and tibia.

          The fibia is smaller than the fibia.

          The fibia is more comonly known as the calf bone.

          The thinest longbone in the human body is the fibia.

          The word fibia comes from the latin, meaning broach or clasp.


        </FactA>
      </Fact>
      <Fact name="Femur"><!-- 10 -->

        <FactA>
          Femur:
          The longest bone in the human body is the femur.

          The strongest bone in the human body is the femur.

          The thigh only contains one bone: the femur.

          Over a ton of force can be applied to the femur without fracturing.

          The Femur extends from the hip to the knee.

        </FactA>
      </Fact>
    </Fact>


  </Facts>
</FactList>